We have covered primary keys and their use in
database tables. Primary keys can also be used
to establish foreign keys, fields that define
one-to-one or one-to-many relationships between
tables. One-to-one relationships
use primary keys from two tables.
One-to-many relationships use a primary key in
one table and a non-primary key in another table.
Here is an example. I have the
Person.StateProvince table design open,
and I want to add a foreign key to
the CountryRegion code field in the
Person.CountryRegion table. Doing this will allow
the country region codes to be looked up from the
CountryRegion table when forms are built for
this database. Columns in relationships do not
need to have the same name, but they do need to
have the same data type. In other words, a text
field has to be related to another text field,
and a number field has to be related to another
number field. To add a foreign key, we want to be
in the table where the foreign key will reside,
not the table with the primary key. I will select
the Table Designer menu and then Relationships.
Then, to add a foreign key relationship, I will
select Add. I will then select the ellipsis
on the Tables and Columns Specification field.
The primary key table is the table we are in, and
the primary key is listed here. I will switch this
to the primary key on the CountryRegion table and
add the CountryRegionCode field below
the table. Then, in the Foreign key
table area, I will choose the table we are
in and the matching CountryRegionCode field.
As we do this, note that the relationship name
builds itself to reference the foreign key table
and then the primary key table. Some believe
that we should add the column name here,
but for now, I will just select the OK button,
the Close button, save the changes to the table,
and then acknowledge that two tables will
be affected as a result of this foreign key.